A Guide to the Rockefeller Family papers, Home Movies and Newsreels FA1303
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Abby (Babs) Rockefeller Family Home Movies, 1928-1934; 3
  - "Looney Tunes by Babs", 1930-1933 (Edit: circa 1960); 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 22 minutes (Reel AV 10738)
    Various locations. "Looney Tunes by Babs" - Milton Family film compilation. Edited by Abby (Babs) Rockefeller Mauze and Abby (Mitzi) O'Neill, c. 1960.
  - Head and Tail cards for "Looney Tunes by Babs", circa 1960; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10739)
    Head and Tail cards for the "Looney Tunes by Babs" compilation. B and O Film Effects.
- Laurance S. Rockefeller Family Home Movies, 1935-1955; 4
  Laurance S. Rockefeller home movies circa 1935-1955. Types of records include: films.
  - Mary French Rockefeller Walks, Pocantico Hills House Under Construction, circa 1935; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 1 minute (Reel AV 10782)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Mary French Rockefeller walks around site of house under construction; plays with dog.
  - Mary French Rockefeller with Newborn Laura in Hospital, 1936 October; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10783)
    New York, NY. Mary French Rockefeller with newborn Laura in hospital. Laura in crib; with nurse; with Mary French Rockefeller in bed; in crib
  - Baby Laura with Nanny, Mrs. Plate, 1937; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10784)
    New York, NY. Baby Laura in highchair being fed by her nanny Mrs. Plate.
  - Mary French Rockefeller with Laura on lawn at Kykuit, Summer 1937; 16mm film; Silent, Color, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10785)
    Color drops out momentarily.
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Mary French Rockefeller with toddler Laura in playpen; on lawn at Kykuit.
  - Mary French Rockefeller and Laura in Central Park - I, Winter 1937-1938; 16mm film; Silent, Color, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10786)
    New York, NY. Mary French Rockefeller and Laura in Central Park: In carriage; walking with pull toy; on bench with Mary French Rockefeller and doll.
    Color drops out momentarily due to repair using black and white footage.
  - Mary French Rockefeller and Laura in Central Park - II, Spring 1938; 16mm film; Silent, Color, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10787)
    New York, NY. Mary French Rockefeller and Laura in Central Park: Leaving 115 E. 67th St. apartment building; in carriage; walking; sitting on lawn.
  - Laura Rockefeller Playing, Summer 1938; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10788)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Laura Rockefeller plays on lawn while nanny watches. In sandbox; on slide; with wheelbarrow.
  - Mary French Rockefeller and Laura on Kykuit Lawn, Summer 1938; 16mm film; Silent, Color, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10789)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Pregnant Mary French Rockefeller and Laura on lawn at Kykuit: by gazebo; by pond; on slide; with donkey.
  - Mary French Rockefeller with Newborn Marion in Hospital, 1938 September; Silent, Color and Black and white, 2 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 10790)
    New York, NY. Mary French Rockefeller with newborn Marion in hospital. Marion in crib; held by Mary sitting in chair.
  - Mary French Rockefeller, Laura, and Baby Marion, Spring 1939; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 1 minute (Reel AV 10791)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Mary French Rockefeller with Laura and baby Marion: watering trees in backyard; sitting together by rock garden.
  - Mary French Rockefeller, Laura, and Baby Marion at Kykuit - I, Summer 1939; 16mm film; Silent, Color, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10792)
    Pocantico Hills, NY.: Mary French Rockefeller, Laura, and baby Marion at Kykuit: Marion in playpen, Laura on tricycle; Mary and girls play at edge of fountain.
  - Mary French Rockefeller, Laura, and Baby Marion at Kykuit - II, Summer 1939; 16mm film; Silent, Color, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10793)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Mary French Rockefeller with Laura and baby Marion at Kykuit: Mary arranges blanket, sits with girls and nine other cousins.
  - Mary French Rockefeller, Laura and Marion at Seal Harbor Club, Summer 1939; 16mm film; Silent, Color, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10797)
    Seal Harbor, ME. Mary French Rockefeller, Laura, and Marion at Seal Harbor Club: Mary sun bathes on deck; with girls in kiddie pool.
  - Mary French Rockefeller Aboard the Motorboat "Sea Beast", circa 1939; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10794)
    Tarrytown, NY. Mary French Rockefeller boards and cruises the Hudson River in the motorboat "Sea Beast."
  - Mary French Rockefeller and Laura with Horses, Summer 1940; 16mm film; Silent, Color, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10795)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Pony cart arrives; Mary French Rockefeller with horse; Laura rides pony with Joe Plick; brief shot of Laurance Rockefeller's house.
  - Mary French Rockefeller, Laura, and Marion at Seal Harbor, Summer 1940; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10796)
    Seal Harbor, ME. Mary French Rockefeller, Laura and Marion arrive at house; at beach - girls on blanket with Mary; play in sand with sticks.
  - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller at Kykuit with Cousins, Fall 1940; 16mm film; Silent, Color, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10798)
    Potantico Hills, NY. Abby Aldrich Rockefeller with cousins dressed in Wild West costumes: riding ponies; group gathered on lawn at Kykuit.
  - Laurance "Larry" Rockefeller Jr. at Seal Harbor, circa Summer 1950; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10799)
    Seal Harbor, ME. Laurance "Larry" Rockefeller Jr.: at children's party; with toy boat, walking down to shore with Laura and Marion; on dock; random shots of sailboats.
  - Horse Show, circa 1950; 16mm film; Silent, Color and Black and white, 5 minutes (Reel AV 10800)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Horse Show: Mary French Rockefeller, Laura, Marion and other cousins ride; carriages; cousins on horseback dressed in various costumes.
  - Mary French Rockefeller on Motorboat "Dauntless", circa 1953; 16mm film; Silent, Color, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10801)
    Fishers Island, NY. Mary French Rockefeller with a group aboard the motorboat "Dauntless." Shots of sail boats; yacht club; pulling into dock.
  - Golf Practice, circa 1953; 16mm film; Silent, Color, 1 minute (Reel AV 10802)
    Amagansett, NY. Mary French Rockefeller, Marion, and man practice golf swing.
  - John D. Rockefeller 3rd with Lucy and Marion Rockefeller on Fishers Island, New York, circa 1955; 16mm film; Silent, Color, 5 minutes (Reel AV 10803)
    Fishers Island, NY. John D. Rockefeller 3rd with a group in row boat; shots of Lucy on "Dauntless;" views of shore; sail boats; Marion boards "Dauntless" from row boat.
- Margaretta (Happy) Fitler Rockefeller Childhood Home Movies, 1931-1940; 5
  - Happy and Family at York Harbor, Summer 1931; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 11 minutes (Reel AV 10804)
    York Harbor, Maine. Happy, Margaretta, William, and George Fitler with friends and family: at beach club; Apple Tree cottage; on boat.
  - Western Hunting Trip, Winter 1932-1933; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 8 minutes (Reel AV 10805)
    Unknown locations. William Fitler and friends: at camp; mountains; horse team; ranch; train station.
  - West Indies Cruise, Spring 1933; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 12 minutes (Reel AV 10806)
    Margaretta and William Fitler with friends: onboard ship; in Nassau; Port au Prince; Jamaica; Colon; and Panama Canal. Includes aerial footage of Canal Zone.
  - Chicago World's Fair, Summer 1933; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10807)
    Chicago, IL. Views of the Century of Progress Exhibition: from the ground and the Good Year Blimp. Film contains no images of Fitler family members.
  - Air Show, Summer 1933; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10808)
    Unknown location. Margaretta Fitler with friends at air show.
  - Western Trip, Summer 1933; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 19 minutes (Reel AV 10809)
    Unknown locations. Margaretta and William Fitler with friends: at ranch; mine; stream; mountains; on horseback.
  - Trip to Cuba, Summer 1934; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 7 minutes (Reel AV 10810)
    Cuba. Margaretta and William Fitler with friends: onboard ship; in Havana; at beach; return voyage.
  - Parties at Filter Home, Spring 1935; 16mm film; Silent, Color, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10811)
    Villa Nova, PA. Happy, Margaretta, William, and George Fitler with friends and family: two parties at Sunset Hill house; Happy with Dr. Wood.
  - Fitler Home, Summer 1935; 16mm film; Silent, Color, 6 minutes (Reel AV 10812)
    Villa Nova, PA. Happy, Margaretta, William, and George Fitler with friends and family: play with hose; flag pole; bikes; views of Sunset Hill house.
  - Fitler Family Western Trip - I, Summer 1935; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 12 minutes (Reel AV 10813)
    Jackson Hole, WY. Happy, Margaretta, William, and George Fitler with friends and family at Bar BC Ranch. Footage includes: rodeo; Royal Gorge; Garden of Gods; Seven Falls; boat; mountains; car.
  - Fitler Family Western Trip - II, Summer 1935; 16mm film; Silent, Colr and Black and white, 16 minutes (Reel AV 10814)
    Jackson Hole, WY. Happy, Margaretta, William, and George Fitler with friends and family at Bar BC Ranch. Footage includes: Jackson Hole, Target Lake; cattle roundup; Yellowstone; Old Faithful.
  - At the Filter Home in Villa Nova, Fall 1935; Winter 1935; 16mm film; Silent, Color, 5 minutes (Reel AV 10815)
    Villa Nova, PA. Happy, Margaretta, William, and George Fitler with friends and family. Playing with dogs; dolls; toy car. Ski and sled around Sunset Hill house.
  - Santa Barbara, California, Spring 1936; 16mm film; Silent, Color, 17 minutes (Reel AV 10816)
    Santa Barbara, CA. Margaretta and William Fitler with friends. At Biltmore Hotel; forest picnic; tennis with Alice and Duke Sedgwick; at beach; on boat.
  - Happy Outside at Sunset Hill House, Spring 1936; 16mm; Silent, Color, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10817)
    Villa Nova, Pennsylvania. Happy at Sunset Hill house plays with flowers; drum; and hose with gardener.
  - Vacation in Sea Girt, Summer 1936; 16mm film; Silent, Color, 8 minutes (Reel AV 10818)
    Sea Girt, NJ. Happy, Margaretta, William, and George Fitler with friends and family. At house; dock; sailboat; beach; pool club; fishing boat; forest.
  - Attending Army-Navy Game, 1936 November 28; 16mm film; Silent, Color, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10819)
    Philadelphia, PA. Happy and George Fitler with family at Municipal Stadium. Includes footage of uniformed cadets, marching band, and football game.
  - Margaretta and William Fitler with Friends, Spring 1937; 16mm film; Silent, Color, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10820)
    Black Point, RI. Margaretta and William Fitler with friends: trapshooting; cutting wood; and on train platform.
  - Filter Family at Beach and on Sail Boats, Summer 1937; 16mm film; Silent, Color, 8 minutes (Reel AV 10821)
    Narraganset, RI. Happy, Margaretta, William, and George Fitler with friends and family: at beach house; ocean; beach club; on sail boat; and boat races.
  - Tennis Tournament, circa Summer 1938; 16mm; Silent, Color, 1 minute (Reel AV 10822)
    Tennis match at unknown location; unknown woman plays tennis. (No images of Fitler family members.)
  - In Hawaii, Winter 1938; 16mm film; Silent, Color, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10823)
    Hawaii. Happy, Margaretta, and George Fitler in Hawaii: at volcano; waterfall; and airfield.
  - At Beach Club, Summer 1939; 16mm film; Silent, Color, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10824)
    Unknown Beach Club. Happy, Margaretta, William, and George Fitler with friends: Happy swims in pool; at cabana; and family at terrace restaurant.
  - Army-Navy Game, 2 December 1939; 16mm film; Silent, Color, 1 minute (Reel AV 10825)
    Image is dark for portion of film.
    Municipal Stadium; Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Happy and George Fitler with family attend football game.
  - In Atlantic City, Summer 1940; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10826)
    Atlantic City, NJ. Happy, Margaretta, William, and George Fitler with friends: on boardwalk; gymnastics and bike riding at house; and visiting park.
- Newsreels, 1924 - 1971; 6; 56 film reels
  Newsreels featuring Rockefeller family members between 1924-1971 (Bulk: 1929-1944). Types of records include: films.
  - New and Intimate Pictures of John D. Rockefeller, 1924; 35mm film; Silent, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 11637)
    Pathe News. John D. Rockefeller Sr., age 85, at Christmas Party in Ormond Beach, Florida.
  - John D., 85, Keeps Muscles In Trim!, 1925; 35mm film; Silent, Black and white, 1 minute (Reel AV 11638)
    Pathe News. John D. Rockefeller Sr., age 85, golfing In Ormond Beach, Florida.
  - Collier's Radio Hour: "Lincoln Day Speech" - John D. Rockefeller Jr., 1928 February 12; 35mm film; Sound, 16 minutes (Reel AV 11654)
    NBC Blue Network. John D. Rockefeller Jr. gives radio broadcast: Lincoln Day Speech. WJZ–NY (660 AM). Audio only.
  - John D. Rockefeller is Filmed at Golf, 1928; 35mm film; Silent, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 11639)
    Fox News. John D. Rockefeller Sr., age 89, golfing in Ormond Beach, Florida with General Adelbert Ames.
  - Winkler Oil Pool, 1928; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 10 minutes (Reel AV 11687)
    Atlantic Refining Co. In this industrial film W.M. Irish, J.V. Van Dyke and E.J. Blum tour the Atlantic Refining Co. Winkler Oil Field, part of the Hendrick oil field in Winkler County, West Texas, April 1928.
  - John D. Rockefeller Talks, 1929; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 11641)
    Hearst Metrotone News. John D. Rockefeller Sr., age 90, reads Standard Oil 60th Anniversary letter in Ormond Beach, Florida. First sound film appearance of John. D. Rockefeller. Contains 16mm outtakes.
  - Rockefeller is 90 Years of Age, 1929; 13mm film; Silent, Black and white, 5 minutes (Reel AV 11640)
    Fox News. John D. Rockefeller Sr. attends his 90th Birthday at Kykuit, Pocantico Hills, New York.
  - Rockefeller Rides in Airplane for First Time, 1930; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 3 minutes (Reel AV 11642)
    Fox Movietone News. John D. Rockefeller Sr. age 90; First Airplane Ride. Miami, Florida.
  - Rockefeller Center Construction Excavation and Marquee of RKO Roxy (demolished), circa 1930; circa 1932; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 30 seconds (Reel AV 11675)
    Rockefeller Center: Two fragments with no titles filmed by unknown movie studio.
  - John D., at 92, Leads Singing on Golf Links, 1931; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 11643)
    Fox Movietone News. John D. Rockefeller Sr., age 92, golfs and sings with Sir Malcom Campbell.
  - John D. Urges Faith!, 1932; 35mm film; Sound. Black and white, 3 minutes (Reel AV 11644)
    Paramount News. John D. Rockefeller Sr.'s 93rd birthday message at Kykuit; Pocantico Hills, New York. Contains outtakes and visible optical track.
  - Rockefeller Centre Seen as Symbol of World Unity, 1932; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 11663)
    Pathe News. John D. Rockefeller Jr. at Rockefeller: British Empire Cornerstone, July, 1 1932, with Lord Southborough. Partial narration is missing.
  - Peek at the Peak!, 1932; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 11676)
    Paramount News. John D. Rockefeller 3rd at Acadia Park Roadway Opening Ceremony, Bar Harbor, Maine - July 23, 1932, with George Dorr, Governor William T. Gardner, Honorable Charles Adams Secretary of the Navy.
  - Start British Unit, 1932; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 11662)
    Paramount News. John D. Rockefeller Jr. at Rockefeller Center: British Empire Cornerstone, July, 1 1932, with Lord Southborough. Contains outtakes at end of film.
  - Rockefeller Grandson Makes Movie Debut, 1932; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 1 minute (Reel AV 11669)
    Pathe News. Nelson A. Rockefeller at Rockefeller Center presenting the Craftsmen Awards.
  - Rockefeller Prizes, 1932; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 5 minutes (Reel AV 11668)
    Paramount News. Nelson A. Rockefeller gives out the Craftsmen Awards to expert craftsmen who were a part of the construction of Rockefeller Center.
  - Charity Plan Begun by Society Sweeps Country by Storm, 1932; 35mm film; Silent, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 11678)
    Universal Newspaper Newsreel. John D. Rockefeller 3rd works with the Greater New York Emergency Unemployment Relief Committee. Soundtrack missing.
  - John D., 3rd Weds!, 1932; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 40 seconds (Reel AV 11683)
    Paramount News. The wedding of John D. Rockefeller 3rd and Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller, November 11, 1932, New York, New York. Couple arrives at Colony Club after Riverside Church ceremony. Partial soundtrack, music only.
  - Front Page Folks, 1932; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 40 seconds minutes (Reel AV 11684)
    Paramount News. John D. Rockefeller 3rd and Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller return from Bermuda honeymoon, December 1932.
  - Restore Old Tavern!, 1932; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 11688)
    Paramount News. Raleigh Tavern Dedication on Sept 16, 1932, Williamsburg, Virginia, with Governor John Garland Pollard. Partial soundtrack; music only.
  - Share the Work!, circa 1933; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 11679)
    Paramount News. Nelson A. Rockefeller: "Share the Work" speech, New York, New York.
  - Rockefeller Tees Up!, 1933; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 11645)
    Paramount News. John D. Rockefeller Sr., age 93, golfing in Ormond Beach, Florida.L
  - J.D. Rockefeller, Jr., Storm Center in Fight on Prohibition Repeal, 1933; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 11655)
    Pathe News. John D. Rockefeller Jr. – Prohibition Controversy Speeches with Senators Sheppard and Bulkley.
  - A Tribute to France, 1933 May; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 6 minutes (Reel AV 11661)
    Paramount News. Nelson A. Rockefeller and Prime Minister Edouard Herriot attend laying of Maison Francais cornerstone at Rockefeller Center. A letter from John D. Rockefeller Jr. is read aloud. Dr. Nicholas Murray Butler from Columbia University and Prime Minister Edouard Herriot give speeches..
  - Rockefeller Heir Weds, 1934; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 11685)
    Paramount News. The wedding of Laurance S. Rockefeller and Mary French Rockefeller, August 22, 1934, Woodstock, Vermont, with Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller Jr., Abby "Babs" Rockefeller, and Mary T. Rockefeller.
  - John D. Rockefeller Sr. at Ormond Beach Train Station (fragments), 1936; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 30 seconds (Reel AV 11646)
    Ramdom shots at train station. Unknown movie studio.
  - Spurs Fingerprint Drive!, 1936; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 11656)
    Paramount News. John D. Rockefeller Jr. participating in the FBI Fingerprint Drive with J. Edgar Hoover. Attorney General Homer Cummings, in Washington, urges public support.
  - Names in the News, 1936; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 1 minute (Reel AV 11650)
    Movietone News. John D. Rockefeller Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller at Versailles and Avenue Rockefeller.
  - John D., Jr. Honored by France, 1936; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 1 minute (Reel AV 11649)
    Pathe News. John D. Rockefeller and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller at Versailles and Avenue Rockefeller.
  - John D. Rockefeller Guest of Honor at Versailles, 1936; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 1 minute (Reel AV 11651)
    Movietone Actualities. John D. Rockefeller Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller at Versailles and Avenue Rockefeller. Narration in French.
  - M. John D. Rockefeller Junior Visite le Chateau de Versailles Restore, 1936; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 40 seconds (Reel AV 11652)
    Pathe-Journal. John D. Rockefeller Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller touring restored Versailles. Narration in French.
  - Unemployment Census Drive, circa 1936; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 30 seconds (Reel AV 11657)
    Paramount News. John D. Rockefeller Jr. presents his unemployment census speech on NBC Radio Network, New York, New York.
  - Rockefeller Dead at 97, 1937; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 11647)
    Pathe News. John D. Rockefeller Sr., age 97, obituary.
  - Final Rites for Rockefeller, 1937; Sound, Black and white, 8 minutes; 35mm film (Reel AV 11648)
    Pathe News. Rockefeller family and body of John D. Rockefeller Sr. arrive at Pocantico Hills, New York, with John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller, and David Rockefeller. Contains outtakes.
  - John D. Rockefeller Jr. Receives Honorary Degree, 1937; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 15 seconds (Reel AV 11653)
    Providence, Rhode Island. John D. Rockefeller Jr. receives honorary Brown LL.D. Fragment from longer film. Movie company unknown.
  - Peace Has a Home, 1937; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 7 minutes (Reel AV 11659)
    Paramount News. International House 13th Anniversary in New York, New York, circa November 18, 1937, with John D. Rockefeller Jr. Footage contains sound and silent outtakes.
  - Rockefeller Millions — The March of Time, 1937; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 6 minutes (Reel AV 11673)
    Rockefeller Center: The March of Time - Volume 3, Number 12 - July 9, 1937
  - Rockefeller Heir Initiated by Circus Saints and Sinners, 1938; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 1 minute (Reel AV 11681)
    Universal Newsreel. Winthrop Rockefeller at Lunch Club Initiation, June 8, 1938, New York, New York.
  - Rockefeller Center Complete, 1939; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 1 minute (Reel AV 11664)
    Movietone News. John D. Rockefeller Jr. at Rockefeller Center: Last Rivet, November 1, 1939, with Nelson A. Rockefeller.
  - Rockefeller in Peace Plea, 1939; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 1 minute (Reel AV 11665)
    Paramount News. John D. Rockefeller Jr. at Rockefeller Center: Last Rivet, November 1, 1939, with Nelson A. Rockefeller.
  - Completed – John D., Jr. Sets Last Rivet at Radio City, 1939; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 11666)
    RKO-Pathe News. John D. Rockefeller Jr. at Rockefeller Center: Last Rivet, November 1, 1939, with Nelson A. Rockefeller.
  - Drive Last Rivet at World's Greatest Building Project, 1994-2004; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 11667)
    Universal Newsreel. John D. Rockefeller Jr. at Rockefeller Center: Last Rivet, November 1, 1939, with Nelson A. Rockefeller.
  - New Home – Modern Art Housed In $2,000,000 Museum, 1939; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 1 minute (Reel AV 11680)
    RKO-Pathe News. Nelson A. Rockefeller attends opening of Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) with Edsel Ford and John Hay Whitney, May 10, 1939, New York, New York. Contains outtakes. Middle section of film is missing.
  - Virginia – Oldest Legislature in Nation Convenes, circa 1939-1940; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 1 minute (Reel AV 11677)
    RKO-Pathe News. John D. Rockefeller 3rd in Williamsburg, Virginia, with British Ambassador Lord Lothian.
  - Lauds Free Press, 1940; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 1 minute (Reel AV 11670)
    Paramount News. Nelson A. Rockefeller at Rockefeller Center: Associated Press Building. Isamu Noguchi "News" Unveiled, April 1940
  - Radio City – Music Hall Honored by N.Y. World's Fair, 1940; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 11672)
    RKO-Pathe News. John D. Rockefeller 3rd at Rockefeller Center - New York World's Fair Tribute: "Rockefeller Center Day" - July 13, 1940 with Grover Whalen, Rockettes, and Corps de Ballet.
  - Youngest Rockefeller Son is Married, 1940; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 45 seconds minutes (Reel AV 11686)